battleofthebands.com 2016-06-29

# Privacy - Battle Of The Bands

Your privacy on the Internet is important to us. As part of our operations, we gather certain types of information about www.battleofthebands.com users, and we would like to explain the types of information we gather, what we do with it and how to correct or change the information.

### 1\. Information Collected

We collect two types of personally identifying information from users: personal data (such as names and e-mail addresses); and aggregated data (such as information about traffic patterns on Battle Of The Bands, for example how many users log into Battle of the Bands on a daily basis).

### 2\. Personal Data

Personal data is collected when users provide personal data to us, for example to become a fan of a particular artist, or other membership services, and registering for contests and other promotional opportunities provided by Ernie Ball or the sponsors of such contests and promotional opportunities. Also, we collect the e-mail addresses of users who post messages to our message boards and comment sections.

### 3\. Aggregated Information

Aggregated information, such as which pages users access or visit and information volunteered by users, such as site registrations, is collected through various methods. For example, Ernie Ball collects IP addresses. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the Web. Web servers, the computers that "serve up" Web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address, and when you request a page from us, our servers log your IP address. We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, so although your session will be logged, you will remain anonymous to us. We collect IP addresses for the purposes of system administration and to provide aggregate data to advertisers about the volume of use on Battle of the Bands

### 4\. Use of Cookies

We also use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that most major Web sites write to your hard drive for record keeping purposes when you visit them. Cookies allow us to measure activity on the www.battleofthebands.com site ("Site") and to improve your user experience, for example by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, thus allowing you to visit various member-only parts of the Site without re-registering. Cookies are used by us to measure activity on the Site and make improvements and updates based on which areas are popular and which are not. We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a cookie.

You may occasionally get cookies from our advertisers, which is standard in the Internet industry. We do not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to our privacy policies.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you set your browser to refuse cookies, it is possible that some parts of the Site, such as the member-only areas, voting areas, and communication areas, will not function properly if you do so. If you need help enabling cookies google has a page with step by step instructions [http://www.google.com/support/accounts/bin/answer.py?&answer=61416](http://www.google.com/support/accounts/bin/answer.py?&answer=61416)

### 5\. Use of Information Collected

Ernie Ball uses both the personal and aggregated information we collect for multiple purposes. The information is used to improve the content of the Site, to customize the content and/or layout of the Site for each individual user and to notify users about updates to the Site or promotional offers or opportunities that we believe will be of interest to you. In addition, any content you submit to the Site (images, voting, comments, etc.) will be publicly available. From time to time employees may examine this content or other user behavior to confirm that the Terms and Conditions of Use are not being violated. When you send email or other communication to Battleofthebands.com, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.

Ernie Ball shares aggregated information with third parties for both advertising and promotional purposes. Ernie Ball may share personal information with sponsors of contests and promotional opportunities on this Site. Ernie Ball may also share personal information with prescreened third parties for marketing or promotional purposes. Ernie Ball will try to provide users with an opportunity to decline this service when such information is requested from you online.

Ernie Ball may also share information with consultants and affiliates for internal business purposes and may divulge personal information if such information is subpoenaed, or if Ernie Ball believes that any user has committed unlawful acts or acts that endanger the health or safety of another user or of the general public. In some situations, we will share your personal information, on a confidential basis, with third parties who perform a particular service on our behalf, such as sending e-mails. Also, Ernie Ball may be sold or transferred to another entity. Should such an event occur, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

Ernie Ball may use third party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Sites. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to the Site and to other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this Site and other sites about goods and services of interest to you. In addition, Ernie Ball may share with such companies Web site usage information about visitors to the Sites for the purpose of managing and targeting advertisements on our sites. For this purpose, we and our third-party advertising sponsors note some of the pages you visit on our sites through the use of pixel tags (also called clear gifs).

### 6\. Children and Privacy

Ernie Ball encourages parents and guardians to spend time with their children online, and to be fully familiar with the sites visited by their children. At various places on BattleoftheBands.com, Ernie Ball will ask whether users are under the age of 18, or 13, for example when requesting personal information from users, or Ernie Ball may ask for parental consent. However, while Ernie Ball requests this information or permission, Ernie Ball relies on users to be truthful in responding to these questions.

### 7\. Individuals Under 13

No information should be submitted to or posted on the Site by users under the age of 13. Ernie Ball does not provide any personally identifying information, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever unless disclosed during collection. Users under the age of 18, but over the age of 13 are required to submit a parental consent form.

### 8\. Individuals 13 Through 17

Ernie Ball requests that children under the age of 18 do not submit or post information to the Site without a parent or guardian's consent. Ernie Ball may collect information, including personally identifying information, from users between the ages of 13 and 17, and with the permission of their parent or guardian this information may be used for marketing and promotional purposes by Ernie Ball and may be shared with sponsors and prescreened third parties. If a user or their parent or guardian changes their mind with respect to such use, such user, parent or guardian may stop that use - either by e-mail request or by modifying his/her registration information online as described above in "Use of Information Collected by Ernie Ball".

### 9\. Message Boards and Comments

Please remember that information posted to message boards and comment areas becomes public information. Use caution when posting. Users under the age of 18 should be especially careful not to provide any personally identifying information while using comments or message boards. As set forth in Ernie Ball's [Terms and Conditions](http://www.battleofthebands.com/info/tos.eb) of Use, users of comments and message boards must follow acceptable standards of behavior when posting messages online.

### 10\. Links to Other Sites

It is important to note that Ernie Ball contains links to sites other than www.battleofthebands.com, and that those sites may not follow the same privacy policies as Ernie Ball. For instance, if you click on an advertisement on BattleoftheBands.com, this will take you away from BattleoftheBands.com and to an entirely different site. This can include links from advertisers, content providers and partners who may use Ernie Ball's logo and/or style as a result of a co-branding agreement. These sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect data and make uses of it that Ernie Ball would not.

The use of any information or materials that you may access at these external sites is purely voluntary. You should not rely on their contents without independent and thorough review of the accuracy, completeness. These external sites may also refer to specific commercial products, processes, or services by trade name, trademark, service mark, manufacturer or otherwise. Unless Ernie Ball has provided specific authority, such references in no way indicate our endorsement, recommendation or preference. This section should be read in conjunction with the full Terms and Conditions of Use.

### 11\. Additional Information

No transmission of data over the Internet is guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of Ernie Ball to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully. While we strive to protect your personal information, Ernie Ball cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. Any such transmission is done at your own risk.

Under no circumstances, including but not limited to negligence, shall Ernie Ball be liable for any special, incidental or consequential damages that result from the use of information or materials on our sites, even if Ernie Ball or an authorized representative of Ernie Ball, has been advised of the possibility of such damages. This section also should be read in conjunction with the full Terms and Conditions of Use. USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR AGREEMENT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE AND PRIVACY POLICY.

Ernie Ball reserves the right to change this policy at any time by notifying users of the existence of a revised privacy policy by posting it on the Site.

You can send e-mail to us with any further questions at [battle@ernieball.com](mailto:battle@ernieball.com).
